familybuilder.com 2013-10-10

# Familybuilder Including Family Tree on Facebook, Newsletters, and Genealogy

We at iFamily Inc., doing business as LiveFamily("LiveFamily," "we", "us" or “our”), are strongly committed to protecting the privacy of personal information of our registered users ("Members"), visitors and unregistered users (collectively "Users" , "you" or “your”) of the LiveFamily.com website (the “Website”) and the Family Tree application (the “Application”) operated by us on a social networking site (“SNS”), such as Facebook. 

We have established this Privacy Policy to provide information regarding the collection and use of your personal information, so that you can make an informed decision about your use of the Website and Application. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to the Website and Application, and not to the SNS. We ask that you please read and accept the privacy policy of the SNS as well. 

**_Information Collected_**

**Personal Information:**

When you use the Website or an Application on a SNS, you allow us to access certain information from your profile from that SNS. The information you allow us to access is affected by the privacy settings you establish at the SNS. For example, LiveFamily may access and store some or all of the following information, as allowed by you, the SNS and your preferences:

  * your “basic information” you have shared with everyone on the SNS
  * your profile picture or its URL
  * your user ID number, which is linked to publically available information such as name and profile photo
  * the login e-mail you provided to that SNS when you registered
  * your “family and relationship” information
  * your “photo and video” information
  * your “friends” information
  * Other information indicated as part of the “Request for Permission” prompt from the SNS

Your agreement takes place when you "accept" or "allow" (or similar terms) our Application on a SNS.

Additionally, LiveFamily asks you for certain information in the course of building your family tree and using other Application functionality that you enter separately including relatives' names, emails, places of birth, dates of birth, and other such information. If applicable, when you add a relative who is also on the SNS to the Application, we pull their publically available information and combination of basic information (gender, dob) and extended information (interests, activities) from their SNS profile and we display that information within the relative's profile. For non-SNS relatives, you can input a number of different fields - date of birth, gender, current location, anniversary date - which is used to create the family tree. 

You may also provide personal information to include in your profile or your family members’ profiles to tell others about yourself or those in your family tree, or when taking advantage of promotions, responding to surveys, or subscribing to newsletters or other lists. 

**Anonymous Information:**

LiveFamily uses cookies to collect information for record keeping purposes and to make it easier to navigate the Website and Application. Cookies are small text files that are stored on Users' hard drives. Our cookies are not linked to your personal information. LiveFamily uses both "session ID cookies" and "persistent cookies." Session ID cookies are used to store information while a user is logged into the Website or Application and expire when the User closes his or her browser. Persistent cookies are used to make tasks like logging into the Website and Application easier for returning Users by remembering a User's login information. Persistent cookies stay on a User's hard drive from one session to the next. You may choose not to receive cookies from LiveFamily by following instructions in your web browser's "help" file, but this may make certain features of the Website and Application inaccessible to you. 

LiveFamily also collects Users' IP addresses and basic log file information (such as address, browser type and language, number of clicks, domain names of web sites visited, pages viewed, the amount of time spent on particular pages, and the date and time) to help locate potential problems with our servers, and to aggregate general user statistics including demographic and geographical information. We use this information to analyze general usage patterns, and to provide advertisements and other services appropriate to the User's location. LiveFamily may aggregate User information in a non-personally identifiable manner to share with advertisers and to enhance the Website or Application with new features. 

**Advertising**

We partner with third party ad networks to either display or manage advertising on our Website or Application. Our ad network partners use cookies, web beacons, javascript, or other tracking technologies to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other websites and applications to provide you targeted advertising based upon your gender, family status, interests, and other criteria. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

LiveFamily does not provide any personal information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks. This data is only shared in the aggregate. However, please note that if an advertiser asks LiveFamily to show an advertisement to a certain audience or audience segment and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks. The LiveFamily.com Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such advertisers. 

**_Use of Information_**

**Personal Information:**

In addition to accessing certain information from your SNS profile as noted above, if you submit personal information to us through the Website or Application, then we use this information to operate, maintain, and provide the features and functionality of the Website and Application. You can set the privacy settings on your applications account to control the access of other Users and Members to the information in your family tree and other application-specific information. You can update your privacy settings under the “Settings” link in the Application. Note that Members can forward this information to other Users or non-users.   

**Email Communications from Us**

By providing LiveFamily your email address you consent to our using the email address to send you service-related notices, including among other things, notices required by law. You may not opt out of service-related e-mails. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, including changes to Application features and special offers and third-party advertisements. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email, or by changing your applications account settings on the SNS, located [here](http://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=privacy) or by contacting us by using the form located [here](http://apps.facebook.com/familytree/report). Opting out will prevent you from receiving promotional email messages regarding updates, improvements, or special offers and advertisements.

If you choose to use our referral service to invite a relative or friend to join our site, we will ask you for your relative’s or friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your relative or friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. We do not store this email address. 

**Anonymous Information:**

We store, track and analyze non-personal information, such as usage data, IP addresses, user preferences and user trends, to improve the quality and design of the Website and Application and to create new features and services. We may use such information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your current or subsequent visits to the Website or Application; (b) provide customized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic; (d) diagnose or fix technology problems; (e) access your information after you sign in; (f) market our Website and Application to advertisers and other third parties; (g) aggregate general User and Member statistics including demographic and geographic information; and (h) other purposes for which your personal identity is not revealed. 

**Posted Information**

Any information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to public areas of the Website or Application (for instance, in the forum or in sections of the Application Home tab) becomes available to the public. 

**Sharing of Information**

LiveFamily will not share your email address with unaffiliated third parties without first obtaining your permission and notifying you at the point of collection. We share your personal information with other carefully selected partner companies so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, please contact us at [support@livefamily.com](mailto:support@livefamily.com). To unsubscribe from these communications, click on the “unsubscribe” link on the email communication. 

## **Agents/Service Providers**

We may provide information, including personal information, to affiliated companies, or subcontractors, so such parties can, among other things (a) perform services and/or process such information on our behalf, (b) use the information to offer greater functionality and enhanced services through the Website and Application, and provide you with additional product and service opportunities, and (c) communicate these opportunities to you. Examples of these service providers are live chat, a virtual currency provider, or an email service provider. 

We share non-personal information (such as anonymous Application use data) with third-parties to assist them in understanding our Application, including Users' use of our Application and the services we provide including the success of advertisements and promotions. 

We may release your information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state or federal laws or respond to a court order, subpoena, law enforcement or regulatory request, or search warrant. We reserve the right to collect and share any information: in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; as appropriate or necessary to enforce our Terms of Use or investigate potential or actual violations of the Terms of Use or Privacy Policy; to take precautions against liability; to protect the security or integrity of our Website and Application; to exercise or protect the rights, property, or the rights and personal safety of LiveFamily affiliates, Users or others; or for other legitimate purposes. 

We may assign or transfer the information we collect to a third party in the event that LiveFamily is acquired by or merged with a third party entity or due to bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or similar situation. 

**Links to Other Sites**

The Website and Application contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Application or Website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personal information. 

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by our Website and Application. 

**Children's Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important and is mandated by U.S. law. For these reasons, LiveFamily does not knowingly collect personal information in the Website or Application from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our Website orApplication is directed to persons under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then you must not use or access the Website orApplication at any time or in any manner or provide any information to the Website or Application. Additionally, Users over 13 years of age must not supply to us or disclose in the Website or Application any personal information (except for a first name only to be used only as a placeholder) of any person under 13 years of age, as we do not intend to collect information from anyone under 13 or invite them to participate in the Website or Application. 

**International Users**

The Website and Application are hosted in the United States and are intended for and directed to Users in the United States. The Website and Application services are void where prohibited. If you are accessing the Website or Application from outside the United States, your use of the Website and Application is governed by U.S. law, you are transferring your personal Information to the United States, and you consent to that transfer.

**Your Choices**

You may, of course, decline to submit personal information to the Website or Application, in which case LiveFamily may not be able to provide certain services to you.

You may update or correct your personal information on the Website or Application by using the Website or Application to edit, delete or change the information. You may also adjust your account settings to determine who has access to your personal information through the Website and Application. You may request that LiveFamily remove information from the Website and Application by contacting us at [support@livefamily.com](mailto:support@livefamily.com) with the understanding that LiveFamily may maintain an archive of the information that you submit outside of the Website and Application. Please note that even if you ask to have your data deleted from the Website or Application, if someone else has added you as a relative, some data may still exist unless that user requests to have the data deleted as well. 

Our Website and Applicationmay offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blogs or community forums, contact us at [support@livefamily.com](mailto:support@livefamily.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Deletion of Your Personal Information and Data Retention:**

If you remove or deactivate the Application on a SNS, we retain the information we have collected about you. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [support@livefamily.com](mailto:support@livefamily.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will respond to your request within 30 business days. 

**Data Security**

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the your personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it, utilizing secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information like SSL, we cannot guarantee its absolute security or that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. 

**Compromise of Personal Information**

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, LiveFamily will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

**Notification Procedures**

It is LiveFamily's policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to Users via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our Website or Application pages, as determined by LiveFamily in its sole discretion. LiveFamily reserves the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to our Users, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

We may update this privacy statement at any time to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on the Website or Application. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. As the Website and Application continue to develop, we may add new services and features. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately and the “last updated” date will be changed. We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy if it has been updated since the last time you have read it.   

**Contact**

Please contact [support@livefamily.com](mailto:support@livefamily.com) with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, the Website or the Application. You can also reach us at Customer Service, iFamily Inc. 500 108th Avenue NE, Bellevue, WA 98004
